Chapter 1: Photography

I guess it's not that unusual for Muggleborns at Hogwarts to have had a hard time fitting in back when they were attending Muggle primary schools. I, for instance, was really never as sporty as most of the other boys at my school. I was never good at playing rounders, and really didn't enjoy it very much, and the other kids – boys mostly, but some of the girls too – made fun of me for the fact that I preferred to mess around with the camera my parents had given me. My mother told me that she never really fit in either, and that if I was just patient that things would get better.

Patient. She had no idea. I guess she probably thought that as my classmates and I grew up, the differences wouldn't be so important. Well, that and the fact that she was also quite certain that I was gifted in the visual arts and that someday what she saw as my immense talents for photography would get the recognition they deserved.

Did she imagine for one moment that the photos I took would come alive when they were developed? How could she? Personally, I was terrified when I found out. I still remember the shock I felt the day I took out the photographs I'd taken at my school's May Day celebration and saw that some of them (only some of them) moved. I was sure I was going crazy, and in my panic, I quickly stashed the moving photos in the shoebox I keep under my bed. When she called me over to show her the beautiful pictures I'd taken, I only showed her the ordinary ones.

She exclaimed how talented I was, as she always does, but I almost lost my lunch when she said, "Look how you've captured the movement of the maypole dance!"

I'm sure I mumbled something like "Er, what?" as I hurried over to take a look, but the photo she was holding looked normal, and she just went on as she normally did. Then a moment later she happened to look up at me, and her face transformed with sudden concern. She said I looked pale as a ghost, and was I feeling ill. I don't really remember exactly what happened after that, except feeling vaguely confused as she herded me off to bed. I think she brought me some tea and dry toast a bit later, but of course I wasn't so much ill as scared. When she came back later she said that I had certainly eaten quickly, that since I looked a lot better, I'd best come down to dinner.

I actually managed to convince myself that I'd only been imagining the thing with the moving photographs, and promised myself I wouldn't think about it any more. I almost managed to forget about the photographs under my bed until a few months later, when I happened to look over the batch I'd taken on the family holiday in Venice. I flipped through comfortingly static shots of the gondaliers steering their boats, and the merchants selling colourful masks.

Then I dropped the stack in alarm as I flipped one over to reveal a lively flock of pigeons descending into a piaza, devouring scattered bread crumbs, and then shifting to hungrily crowd around a gaudily dressed American tourist who wasn't emptying his bag of crumbs quickly enough to satisfy the flock.

Dennis came in just then, and I hurriedly shoved the remainder of the photos into the shoebox, before gathering up the "safe" pictures I'd already looked at to show to Mum who I knew would be waiting downstairs. I didn't escape without rousing his suspicion, though. Little brothers have a way of making life difficult. They always come in at awkward moments, and never know when to leave well enough alone.

"What are you doing?" he wanted to know.

"Nothing."

"What's in that box? Is it alive?"

Dennis was always obsessed with insects, birds, and animals. I happened to know that he had a pet tarantula he kept hidden in a box in the back of our closet. The tarantula's name was Rose, and if Mum had known he had her, she would have thrown a fit.

Sometimes when Dennis thought he was alone he used to take Rose out of the cage-box she came in and talk to her by name. He said that she could understand him, and that she always let him know when she was hungry for crickets. Not knowing about magic at the time, I of course thought this was extremely childish, and a little daft. Maybe I should have wondered a bit after the weird photos that had developed from my camera, but at the time I was still sure that all that was in my head. Well, almost sure.

"It's just my stuff, and it's not your business. How's Rose?"

Dennis looked defensively at the closet, and I knew that as soon as I left the room he'd hurry over to check on the spider. So I took my time. I got up, headed for the door, then casually ambled back to the nightstand to get the little pile of safe photos from Venice, dawdled a little bit as if perusing our bookshelf, and then wandered downstairs. I could hear Dennis scrambling for the closet after I left, and smiled a little.

I found Mum reading at the kitchen table, and sat down next to her. When she looked up, I said, "Here are the best photographs from Venice, Mum. I know you wanted to see them," and handed her what I had. She smiled and put down her book to take a look. With a little bit of embarrassment I listened as she cooed over each one in turn. "Look at the colour!", "Beautiful composition in this shot from the mask shop!", and so on. She said that I was talented beyond my years and that I should find a way to show these in a gallery somewhere. I mostly shrugged these remarks off. Appreciation is great and all, but she's my mum, and I don't even know what she means by "composition." I just took the snapshots that I thought would look nice.

When she'd finished showering praise and insisted on putting a couple of them into the family album, I took the remainder upstairs. I walked quietly, working to time things so that I could walk in on Dennis playing with his tarantula and make him feel uncomfortable.

I walked in to find him sitting on my bed. He knows I don't like it when he does that, but I barely noticed where he was sitting, once I took in what he was doing. My shoebox was open on the bed next to him, and he was holding the thick stack of photographs and gaping at the pigeon picture.

"This is bloody brilliant!" he said, and then added "Rose thinks so too. How did you do it?"

"I don't care what bloody Rose thinks," I told him, "You stay out of my stuff, and keep that tarantula off of my bed, or I'll tell Mum!" I added the last part as he guiltily got up from my bed, setting the photographs aside, and turned to pick up Rose who had been sitting on the bed next to him.

He shuffled over to his own bed, and then sat there holding Rose, and asked again, "How did you do it? You're always fussing with that camera, but I've never heard of anybody taking photographs that could move!"

After a moment, I went over to my bed, carefully brushed off the area where the spider had been sitting, and threw myself down on my bed. I was furious, but I guess I was also relieved: I wasn't insane. Dennis could see the pictures move too.

Another minute later, he asked again, "How did you do that?"

"I don't know," I said. I really had no idea. "It just happened. I honestly thought I'd gone daft." And then I realized how relieved I really felt. "Do you have any ideas?" I asked.

I didn't know whether to be annoyed or what, when he first shrugged, and then looked at the spider as if he thought maybe she'd have something to add. Then he just shrugged again, and said, "Not really. Have you showed these to Mum and Dad?"

It was really good to have somebody to talk to, and we debated for a while about the wisdom of showing something this weird to our parents. In the end I decided to put it off until the next morning, and to try to figure out the right way to bring it up, and maybe show one of the May Day photos to Dad tomorrow. The several moving pictures of the maypole dance somehow seemed less startling than the pigeon picture. I don't know why. Probably something about the cyclic movement of the children holding the coloured ribbons. There was just so much going on in the pigeon picture. People wandering in and out of the frame, and interacting differently with the pigeons all the time. The maypole picture was just more believable. I almost felt like I'd seen something similar in a travelling hologram exhibit we saw one time.

So, I planned: I'd show the photo to Dad, and ask if he'd ever seen anything like it. I wouldn't say I'd taken it, and he probably wouldn't notice that it was the pole from our own school's fair. Maybe he would have an explanation.

Author's notes: The next chapter should be published on or before January 15, 2014.

Chapter 3: Fixus Everythingus

So that was the first introduction that my brother and I ever had to the world of magic. It was two years from that summer to the day that Dennis received his own letter. Back when my letter arrived, none of us had any idea that he was a wizard as well.

On the day I received my letter, Dennis was of course very interested in everything that happened when Professor Flitwick returned and demonstrated a fascinating selection of simple spells (with particular emphasis on Charms of course). And of course Dennis was also extremely disappointed that he wouldn't get to come along when Flitwick took me on my first shopping trip in Diagon Alley the following week. The whole family did come along on the trip to London, though, and he was somewhat placated when Mum and Dad announced that while Flitwick took me shopping, they would be taking him to the London Zoo. And later on I gave him a hefty stack of moving photographs from the shopping trip. He was absolutely beside himself.

I didn't see Dennis much over the year that followed, though at some point it did occur to me to wonder about his relationship with that spider of his, and whether he might be a wizard as well. Mostly, though, I was preoccupied with learning the ropes at Hogwarts.

I'm not quite sure how much I should write about my own Hogwarts experiences before Dennis joined me. I suppose I'm going to have to write a bit about them just to provide context. If you're a Muggle, you might be imagining that life at Hogwarts would be radically different from your everyday existence, and if you talk to some of the older Muggleborn students, that's probably exactly what they'd say. But that was before Harry Potter-Evans-Verres arrived and, with the help of the then Defense professor, turned everything upside-down. Or right-side-up, really. I guess it sort of depends on your perspective.

Anyway, when I finally boarded the Hogwarts Express, I ended up sitting with a bunch of the Weasley kids. Ginny Weasley is in my year, and Mrs. Weasley helped me out with the whole Platform 9 3/4 thing, so it seemed natural enough to sit with them. When George Weasley sat down across from Ron, Ginny, and me, he immediately picked up the shiny new copy of Introductory Physics from the top of his stack of very old and ratty looking leatherbound textbooks on far more interesting-looking topics, flipped through it, and shook his head in frustration.

"Yeah, I don't think I'll ever forgive him for this," Fred said, looking over at the book in his twin's lap.

"I always said there was something wrong with him," Ron muttered.

George closed the book, but continued to hold it in his lap. "Easy now," he said, "Look, he did save her, didn't he? Still... I think these textbooks are actually more expensive than new Transfiguration books would be. The whole thing is mad."

After a pause, he went on, "Really, though, we don't know that the new books are because of Harry."

"Oh, come off it," said Ron, "What other explanation is there?"

I thought I could mostly follow the conversation, though I wasn't sure, and I wouldn't have felt comfortable interrupting the older boys to ask what I was sure would be stupid questions. Given the brand new book in each stack, though, it was pretty clear that science was new to the Hogwarts curriculum. As Ron and his brothers got deeper into their argument about Harry, the new textbooks, and whether the twins were going to bother staying at Hogwarts for another year if they kept having to buy new books, I eventually leaned close to Ginny and asked about the one thing I was sure I didn't know anything about, "Saved who?"

"Hermione Granger," she whispered back, "Fred and George are sensitive about it because they didn't get to her before she died. Harry Potter and last year's Defense professor brought her back, so it's hard for them to stay mad. They're still furious about the number of galleons we had to put down this year for books, though. Me, I'm really glad that first years don't have any new classes other than Basic Arithmancy. That used to be an upper level elective, you know, so I can use Percy's old book. And Fred and George are sharing new books. Plus next year I can use hand-me downs from Ron. So it'll only be a few years of extra expenses for the family. I'm sure we'll get by." She bit her lip, and I got the feeling we were in sensitive territory, so I tried to steer the subject away from textbook prices.

"You said that this Harry person brought back, uh... what was her name again?"

"Hermione Granger. She'll be a second year now."

"Yeah, so Harry brought Hermione back from the dead. Is that a thing we can do? As witches and wizards I mean? Is it something we'll learn at Hogwarts, like?"

Ginny shook her head, "It's only been done that one time. No one is quite sure how it worked, either. And even the most powerful wizards are scared to try to repeat the ritual."

"Why's that?"

"Strange side effects. They're still trying to figure it all out."

"Erm... so how did she, erm... how did Hermione die?"

To my great surprise, when I posed this question, Ginny gave a strange little smile and she said, "Speaking of side effects..." Her eyes shone with mischief as she looked over at her big brothers and said sweetly, "So, George, have you managed to remember how exactly Granger died yet?"

Both twins looked over angrily, evidently to the annoyance of Ron who looked as though he'd been about to say something dreadfully witty about Harry and the textbooks.

"Do not start this up again," said Fred.

"This shite isn't funny Ginny," said George, "You weren't there."

"You have no idea what it was like."

"You wait 'til you see one of your schoolmates burned to a crisp by dragonfire," George continued.

"Or kissed by a dementor," Fred went on.

The twins looked at each other with a sort of resigned confusion, then sighed.

"In any case," said George, "You don't know what it was like. It was bad."

"Evidently you don't know what it was like either, since you can't seem to agree on what happened," said Ginny softly, but I had the impression she was mostly saying it for my benefit, and that the Weasleys had been over this conversation many times before. "The really funny part is, I distinctly remember that when they got home from Hogwarts last summer Fred and George were both talking about how horrible it was seeing Hermione's head bitten off by a cave troll. All of this was before Fixus Everythingus, of course..."

"Fixus Everythingus?"

Ron explained quietly, "That's what everyone is calling the ritual that Harry and Professor Quirrel performed last summer. Everybody's memory has been mucked with."

"David Monroe," said Ginny.

"What?" said Ron.

"David Monroe," Ginny repeated, "Quirinus Quirrel was just his pseudonym, remember?"

Ron grumbled something like, "Quirrel, Monroe, name doesn't matter, the man's a creep."

"So the ritual messed with the memories of everybody who was there?" I asked.

"No, no, no," said George, "Best as we can tell, everybody's memories were affected."

"I haven't noticed anything weird," I said, cautiously.

"Hrm, you know, I haven't heard anything about Muggle Britain being affected," said Ron.

None of the others had either, evidently. So I let the question sit. That conversation was the first time I heard about the Ritual of Fixus Everythingus. It was far from the last. In fact, it was pretty much the only thing Hogwarts students talked about during my first year. There are all kinds of stories about exactly what happened in the spring and summer before I started at Hogwarts, but most of them are variations on what I heard from the Weasleys that first day on the train. The basic story goes something like this...

Basically, it's clear that some very strange things happened in the spring of 1992, all centered around a magic-intensive ritual performed by Harry and the professor of Defense Against the Dark Arts. There evidently used to be a kind of superstition around the position of Defense professor, so when things started to get weird, I guess nobody was surprised that he was involved. Given what I've heard about the activities of previous Defense professors, though, I guess the whole thing was probably a pretty big relief to most people. In fact, I guess a lot of people would say that it was (literally!) the best thing that could have happened.

Magical Britain certainly was happy enough to elect David Monroe as Minister of Magic after the dust settled, so they seemed ready enough to forgive what he and Harry did. He's a very popular Minister, too. Handsome, charming, well-spoken, and most people celebrate what they call his no-nonsense approach to everything. There are only a few people like Ron who still think there's something wrong with Monroe. In his collaborations with the Lucius Malfoy, who is currently acting as Chief Warlock of the Wizengamot, Minister Monroe seems to have done wonders to increase Muggle-awareness among witches and wizards, if not universal Muggle-tolerance. Well, maybe some of those changes had to do with the ritual as well. There are reasons why everyone refers to it as "The Ritual of Fixus Everythingus." It didn't fix everything, obviously, but a lot of things are a lot better. Wizard-Muggle relations is one of them. Hermione later told me that the Muggle phobia she had to deal with when she first arrived was something horrible. I definitely didn't encounter any of that when I got here, and I'm not sure how much of that could be explained by the Minister alone. Nor am I at all sure that the Ministry would have had much influence over McGonnagall's decision to change the name of Hogwarts.

At any rate, there's a lot we don't know about Fixus Everythingus. It does seem pretty clear that the reason that Harry and Mr. Monroe invented this ritual in the first place was to bring Hermione Granger back from the dead. And in that sense, no one can disagree that it worked. Hermione is not only alive, but is doing great. I see her every week at the Chaos Club meetings, and she's generally the most talkative person there. On the other hand, it's also clear that even now she's really angry with Harry. Neville told me once that Harry and Hermione used to be best friends. Not anymore. Neither of them talks openly about it in public, but everybody can tell it's somehow related to the ritual. And that's not even touching the weird memory effects or the other strange stuff that's happened, some of it very disturbing. I don't really know what Harry was expecting from the ritual, but I'm pretty sure he didn't get whatever it was. Ron disagrees about this by the way. He hates Harry and Monroe both, and can't seem to decide that whether he'd prefer to assume the that the side effects were gross incompetence or simply what the two dark wizards intended all along. Ron's in the minority though. Most witches and wizards are happy to embrace Fixus Everythingus as a new and powerful light ritual, but given the side effects, it is also generally accepted that Fixus Everythingus is also an extremely dangerous ritual, only to be attempted by the most proficient wizards and witches, and only after thorough review by the Ministry of Magic.

What makes the ritual so hazardous? If the rumor mill is to be believed, even the ritual's inventors don't know the answer. Even the specific side effects are not well-known. Asside from the memory issues, it seems that some people's personalities changed as well, though it's even more difficult to pin down the exact changes than to get a consistent report of the events that occurred that year. That's not all, though. It was that first day on the Hogwarts Express that I heard the most unsettling rumor associated with Fixus Everythingus:

"I mean," said Ron, "I don't see how everybody can be so certain that Fixus Everythingus is a light ritual. It was right afterward that Dumbledore took himself over to the Department of Mysteries and voluntarily walked through the Veil."

The Veil, I learned, is a mysterious artifact kept at the Department of Mysteries that everybody seems to agree is the gateway to the land of the dead, or at least that it kills you, anyway. In any case, nobody has crossed it and ever come back.

"Yeah, well," Fred had responded, "Good riddance, anyway. Dumbledore was trouble. If it hadn't been for him, Hermione wouldn't have died in the first place."

Ron couldn't let that stand, though, "No way. Dumbledore was the greatest wizard who ever lived. And he'd still be our Headmaster if it weren't for that little creep Harry."

George just shrugged, and Ginny looked at me as if to say, "You see?"

Everyone was quiet for a bit and then George spoke suddenly, "Hey, Ron, did you see the recordings of the school championship Quidditch match between Durmstrang and The Brazilian Wizarding School? What'd you think of that save by Krum?"

I didn't know what Quidditch was, but I could tell where things were going: this was going to be a long and animated conversation about sport. I glanced at Ginny, hopefully, since a lot of times girls aren't into sport, but she was leaning in just as enthusiastically as Ron. I let the four of them, Ginny, Ron, and the twins, go on for about five minutes before I decided that I was correct in my suspicion that it was going to be one of those conversations. At that point, I quietly took my leave to see if I could find a quieter compartment. Maybe I could start reading my Charms textbook. That looked intersting.

I tried to wave to everybody when I left, but they were all too preoccupied to respond, so I just shrugged and left.

Author's notes: The next chapter should be published on or before February 14, 2014.

Chapter 4: Luna

The next two train compartments to where the Weasleys were sitting were packed with students, so there was no chance of my sitting there. When I opened the door to the third compartment, the three girls inside were talking seriously in intense whispers. I wasn't sure what to do, and as I stood gaping with the door opened, the one with the lightest colour hair, who wore wizard robes with green trim stood up angrily and forced the door closed in my face, saying something like, "Haven't you ever heard of privacy?"

I was startled and wandered on a little shakily. I opened the next door much more cautiously. The compartment was nearly empty, but I hesitated before entering. The only person in the room was a blond, round-faced, nice-looking girl sitting by the widow. She looked over at me for a moment, and then looked back out the window. This wasn't the most welcoming response, but I was tired of checking doors, and after a moment I said, carefully, "Is... would it be alright if I joined you in here for a while?"

At that, she turned again, and this time smiled warmly, so I came in and closed the door behind me. She still hadn't said anything. We sat in slightly awkward silence for a bit before I got my courage up again, "My name's Colin," I said softly.

"I'm Luna," she said. Her voice was almost eerily calm. She had a chrysanthemum behind each ear and was wearing a quartz necklace.

More silence.

Eventually I broke the silence again, "Erm, so, erm... Have you been to Hogwarts before?"

"Oh, no, I'm a first year." Still that same strange sleepy-tranquil voice.

"Oh, good. Me too." I couldn't believe how my capacity for normal conversation seemed to have suddenly escaped me.

I just sat there for a moment, until finally she seemed to realize something. Then she visibly relaxed and seemed to open up a bit more, "You're Muggleborn, aren't you?" she asked.

"Erm, yes, how did you...?"

"It's obvious, isn't it?"

"Erm, what?"

"Well, everybody in Wizarding Britain knows who I am because of my dad."

I didn't know what to say to that, so just looked at her.

"They all think I'm daft, don't they?"

"Because of your dad?"

"Sort of. Oh, of course I forget. There must be so much that you don't know!" she raised her hand to her mouth in a style I might have seen in an actress in a really old movie one time. Her huge eyes opened even wider.

"Erm, so, your dad is somebody important, then?" I floundered.

"Only the editor of a major newspaper," she reached into her bag, pulled out a copy of The Quibbler, and shoved it toward me, "Most people don't understand what Dad is doing, though."

The typesetting of the front page distinctly reminded me of The Daily Mirror, and the front page headline read, "Fixus Nothingus? Lives Ruined by Mysterious Ritual."

I stared at the headline as she went on, "It doesn't help, of course, that Dad has a sense of humor. When I was younger I used to talk about my dreams a lot. I guess I said some really weird things, but also kind of just the sort of strange things that kids say sometimes, you know?"

When I looked up from the headline and nodded uncertainly, she went on, "Dad would create whole satirical news stories around the things I said. But people didn't understand, and would make fun of him. And now they all think I'm bonkers, of course."

"Oh." I said stupidly. And then because I didn't quite know what else to say, added, "I'm so sorry." I honestly didn't have any idea what I was supposed to say. The whole conversation felt strange. But I found myself liking Luna anyway. Most of our Hogwarts classmates don't think much of her, and a lot of people say that she looks like a frog, describe her eyes as bulging, but I never thought so. She is... peculiar... though.

"Thanks for coming in, by the way," she said.

"It was nothing," I said, "Honestly, I'm glad to find somebody who seems friendly. I was sitting with the Weasleys before, do you know them?"

She nodded her head with a tired look that seemed to say, "Who doesn't?"

"...but they started going on about sport, and it's really not my thing, you know? And then the girls in the compartment next to yours shut me out..."

"Daphne, Susan, and Hermione," Luna cut in, "They shut themselves up in there as soon as the train started accepting passengers. Can't say I blame them. Hermione never asked to be a celebrity, you know. The whole thing is such sad business..."

"Sad? But isn't Hermione..."

"Oh, I don't mean sad for Hermione, although of course it's hard for her being the first person ever to be brought back," Luna hurried on, "I mean for everybody else."

"You mean like the old Headmaster of Hogwarts? Dumble... um... chap? What was his name?"

"Dumbledore? Oh, yes, that's a nasty business too, of course. No, I meant for people less... directly affected. Take poor Professor Trelawney, for instance." She pointed to the headline in the newspaper she'd passed to me, so I picked up the newspaper and settled down to read.

Next to the headline was an enormous photograph of Sybill Trelawney, who gazed off to the left side of the image so intently that it might as well not have been a moving photograph. The article was all about the difficult situation she was in now that she'd been sacked from Hogwarts. It hinted that there were others similarly affected but didn't give any specifics. Ms. Trelawney used to teach an upper level elective called Divination, I learned, but Hogwarts was doing away with Divination entirely, now, and Professor Trelawney didn't know where she'd go or what she'd do.

When I looked up to indicate that I was finished reading, Luna continued, "She has the True Sight, Professor Trelawney. I know. I'm a little touched myself..." she trailed off briefely and then hurried on, "Oh, not in the way they think. I do wish Dad hadn't actually used my name in all of those articles. Anyway, it is most unfortunate that Trelawney won't be staying at Hogwarts."

"The article says that the new Headmistress... McGonnagall, is it?... offered her the option to stay at Hogwarts as unofficial faculty." I wasn't quite sure what to think of Luna at that stage, but decided to keep an open mind. She certainly seemed nice enough.

"That's true," said Luna, "But it's hard enough for Diviners to find their way in the world. So many people say that Divination is the one branch of magic with no real basis. Prophecies are one thing. Everybody knows those are real. But too few wizards and witches fully embrace general intuition, or the fact that most Seers have abilities far beyond their unusual sensitivity to time pressure. It's a loss for us all, not having somebody like Professor Trelawney teaching at Hogwarts. And disrespectful, too, given that it was Seers like her who discovered magic in the first place."

"Oh, did they?" I asked. I still wasn't sure what to think at that point. In some ways I still don't. If I'd grown up in Magical Britain, I probably would have dropped out of the conversation right there. After all, everybody knows that magic was first manipulated in the lost city of Atlantis... and that all Atlantian records have long since been lost. How could someone like Luna have knowledge still lost to wizarding scholars the world over? And yet, in other ways I'm still not sure.

As it was, since I'd been raised by Muggles, I didn't have much basis for evaluating statements made by other witches and wizards, and while I was starting to get the impression there was something off about her, I also wasn't in a position to dismiss the things she said. Looking back, I'm thankful for that. She's been a good friend.

Just at that moment, though, she glanced out the window and started in surprise, then said quickly, "We're almost there! You'd better get into your robes. I'll see you at the Feast!"

Author's notes: The next chapter should be published on or before March 1, 2014.

Chapter 5: Arrival

I hurried back to the compartment where I'd been sitting with the Weasleys to get my robes out of my luggage, and changed as quickly as I could. The train had already stopped by the time I was dressed, and the Weasleys were filing out.

Halfway out the door, George called, "Hey, mate!" passing me a small card, the size of a business card as I scrambled to gathered my things, "I didn't get a chance to give you this before you ran off before."

The card announced the first meeting of Chaos Club. I didn't know what that was, and tried to ask, but George just told me to be there, and handed me a few more cards, suggesting that I pass them on to other first years. Then when I told him I didn't even know where or when the club was going to meet he explained the card was under enchantment and would vibrate when the time and place displayed. Then he hurried off, followed by Ron who paused to roll his eyes and say, "I wouldn't even bother, if I were you," before running off to catch up with one of his classmates, leaving me alone.

I was the last one off the train, and it took me a while to spot the other first years, all gathered around the truly enormous, rather disheveled, and (I remember thinking after I noticed the sword-like knife in his belt) absolutely terrifying man I later learned was Rubeus Hagrid, the Hogwarts groundskeeper. I might have turned and run if I hadn't seen Luna standing near him and smiling at my tranquilly.

When I finally caught up with the group, I was relieved that Mr. Hagrid didn't really pay much attention to me, just turned, beckoned, and repeated, "This way," before silently leading us down to the docks. I was glad to be able to sit next to Luna as we sailed over black choppy water with the giant. Ginny caught up with me later on, as we were getting off of the boats. I introduced her to Luna, who turned out to only really know the Weasleys in a vague sort of way. I was momentarily worried as I recalled Luna saying that most wizards and witches think she's daft, but they shook hands politely, Luna daintily taking Ginny's strong hand.

Ginny jumped straight into conversation, announcing she'd heard that there wouldn't be a Sorting Ceremony for us, and asking what we thought that was about.

I of course had no idea what the Sorting Ceremony even was, but Luna had an answer, "Actually, Professor Trelawney mentioned that when she was at our house to be interviewed. Headmistress McGonnagall hopes it will reduce bullying. The new headmistress wants that to be part of her legacy, less bullying at Hogwarts. And Trelawney said that most of the fighting between Hogwarts students has been between houses."

I remember Ginny nodded in comprehension, "That makes sense. Ron says that last year when Monroe's Armies were most active there was a lot of fighting between armies, but that up until then most of the fighting had been between houses." She paused, frowned thoughtfully for a moment, and then went on, "You know, now that I think about it, I think George said that Harry Potter had an explanation for this. Something about people how people naturally tend to sort themselves into groups, and to defend the group they identify with. I think he called it 'tribal cues' or something like that."

When I interrupted to ask what the Sorting Ceremony was, Ginny obliged, "Traditionally, and all the traditions at Hogwarts are ancient, each entering class of first years would be sorted into one of the four Houses of Hogwarts based on personality and goals."

"So many changes this year," Luna said had said dreamily, "The first year Hogwarts has ever changed its curriculum. The first year with no Sorting. One has to wonder whether McGonnagall has considered the larger implications."

Ginny smirked a little, but simply asked, "Larger implications?"

"Oh yes," said Luna, "Karmically speaking the implications are huge, of course, but also in other ways. You cannot teach an old hippogriff new tricks. Or at least, not without ending up with an angry hippogriff. And Hogwarts is a very old hippogriff indeed."

Ginny giggled, "I like you, Luna. You're odd, but I like you."

Mr. Hagrid herded us through a small door in the side of the fortress-like structure that was Hogwarts, into a chamber dimly lit by torches on the walls. On the four walls of the room were four massive oil-paintings, each a larger-than-life portrait of a distinguished-looking man or woman, each accompanied by an animal of some sort. Like my magical photographs, the portraits seemed to be alive, and the subjects watched us with a sort of vague interest as we filed in.

When we were all inside and gathered in an awkward cluster, a door next to each painting opened, and a man or woman silently entered to stand next to each painting. I was a little surprised by this since one of the doors was in the same wall through which we'd entered and I'd only seen one door on the outside. Of the people who entered, I recognized Professor Flitwick immediately, as he moved to stand next to the painting of the tall thin woman with the raven perched on the back of her chair. The raven in the painting flapped about as it inspected us with more blatant curiosity and rather less dignity than did the woman in the painting who peered at us over the top of the book she was holding.

The people who entered were the Heads of House, I soon learned: Professor Flitwick for Ravenclaw, Professor Snape for Slytherin, Professor Sprout for Hufflepuff, and Professor Lupin for Gryffindor. With the exception of the raven, the animals in the portraits corresponded to the emblems of the four houses. One time I asked Flitwick why Rowenna Ravenclaw hadn't been painted with an eagle, and he sighed and stated that all the accounts confirm that she'd never had an interest in falconry. He's normally happy to answer questions, but I suppose he gets asked that one quite frequently.

Once the Heads of House were in position, the Headmistress herself entered through a large pair of double doors in one corner of the room. She welcomed us to the school briefly, and explained about the new sorting system:

"Welcome to Hogwarts. As many of you will have inferred, there are a number of changes to Hogwarts policy this year. Among them, the Sorting Hat will not be sorting first years among the four Houses as has occurred in years past. Instead, to promote greater school integrity, your first year house has been determined by the use of a random number spell." As she spoke, I noticed the portrait of Helga Hufflepuff standing up a little taller and nodding in approval, while the other portraits seemed to slump slightly. The man with the snake seemed about to speak, but ducked his head in apology when the Headmistress glared at him.

Headmistress McGonnagall went on, "You will sleep in the dormitories of your assigned house, and will have your meals at the house tables. Do not become too comfortable with your house assignments, however! Houses will be reassigned each year, henceforth, for howsoever long as I serve as Headmistress of Hogwarts. Professors Flitwick, Lupin, Snape, and Sprout each have a list of new student names, which they will read off once I have proceeded to the Great Hall. They will also explain the historical significance of the four houses, so that the traditional values of the houses shall not be lost." The portrait of Godric Gryffindor nodded gruffly at this, though the Ravenclaw and Slytherin portraits continued to look skeptical.

With that, the Headmistress exited through the double doors, which silently closed behind her. The moment the doors closed, everyone seemed to begin speaking at once. The Headmistress's announcement was evidently rather a startling one, and all of the Wizard-born first years seemed to have something to say about it. Eventually the confusion died down, and the four Professors each took a turn reading off names. Ginny and I were both to be housed in Slytherin, we learned, while Luna would be in Gryffindor. Ginny looked up at the portrait of Salazar Slytherin rather warily after we heard we'd be living in his house for the next year, and he glared down at me with utter contempt. "Slytherin never cared for Muggleborns," Ginny explained in a whisper. Our new Head of House didn't seem so welcoming either, but he seemed equally unfriendly toward all of the new residents of Slytherin.

Author's notes: Apologies for slight delay in release of Chapter 5. Chapter 6 should be published on or before March 15, 2014.

Chapter 6: Welcoming Feast

Once we'd learned what houses we'd be living in, and a few of the Wizard-born students were beginning to wonder aloud whether we would now be able to go eat, Professor Sprout called out for everybody to quiet down, and explained that we would now enter the Great Hall where we would sit at our House tables, but that before the food arrived we would get to meet the Sorting Hat after all. The new Sorting Ceremony would not sort us into houses, but into likely future careers. This Career Sorting would foster more personalized mentoring by Hogwarts faculty, she explained.

Ginny has her doubts about the usefulness of this new type of Sorting, given that we all still take the same core classes and still get to choose our electives. She reckons that the real purpose of the new Sorting Ceremony is so that the Sorting Hat doesn't go insane with boredom. She actually mentioned this hypothesis at one of the early meetings of Chaos Club, which launched a lively debate. Harry Potter-Evans-Verres was uncharacteristically silent for that discussion, and mostly sat there looking uncomfortable while the conversation ran its course. I never found out why he reacted that way, but I guess it's probably related to a rumour I heard that at some point after the Welcoming Feast, older students were given the option of Career Sorting if they wanted, but that the Hat had refused point-blank to be placed onto Harry's head.

Whether Ginny's idea is right or not, during our Career Sorting, the Sorting Hat announced that Ginny was well suited to work in the Ministry, that Luna should be prepared for training as a Healer, and that I was likely to go on to a career in journalism. I wonder whether part of Ginny's scepticism is rooted in annoyance at the suggestion that she might follow in her father's footsteps. For other students, the Sorting Hat suggested careers like Auror (for any Muggles reading this, that's the name for the police in Magical Britain), magical artefact development, or banking. There were gasps of shock all around the room at the first mention of banking, and I heard a couple of students at the Slytherin table mutter things about how the goblins wouldn't be happy, or quietly grumbling that we were headed for another goblin rebellion.

Once we'd all settled ourselves again, the Headmistress stood up from the teachers' table, and spoke in her loud strong voice, "Welcome to a new year at Hogwarts!" and then I heard a catch in her voice, almost as though she were about to cry, as she continued, "Before we begin our banquet, I would like to say a few words." She paused, then took a deep breath before going on, her voice strengthening once more as she spoke, "No, I am no Albus Dumbledore, and there is no replacing him. He was not always the wisest of Headmasters, but it is nevertheless a great honour to have had the privilege of calling him my colleague. However," and here the tall witch smiled slightly, "in his honour, let me repeat for you a few words that he would have liked for you to hear: Nitwit! Blubber! Oddment! Tweak! Thank you." And so saying, she sat down again to a rather sedated round of applause from the school.

At this moment, the Hogwarts House Elves, who had been lined up in the back of the Hall, clapped their hands in unison, and dishes of hot food floated out of a hidden doorway, landing gently on the five tables. The food was quite good, though nothing like home. I was ravenous, which I guess makes sense. It had been a long day: train ride, encounter with a giant, boat ride, finding out where I'd be living for the next year, and Career Sorting. Anyhow, I ate quickly, focused on little else, and was barely finished when I slowly realized that the Great Hall had fallen into a sort of hush of anticipation. All eyes were on the Faculty Table, and when I followed the collective gaze, I saw that Headmistress McGonnagall was standing up again. Looking back, I suppose that most of the student body had been waiting rather impatiently for the more substantial speech traditionally given by the Headmistress or Headmaster at the end of the Welcoming Feast.

So many changes this year, Luna had said. Of course the students were waiting. Most the speech that followed focused school policy, which evidently was not very different from previous years, then something about Quidditch tryouts with reference to the elimination of one of the positions. There was a general murmur of resigned discontent at that. Finally, she went on to discuss the changes in course offerings and to introduce new faculty. Based on the responses of my classmates, this was the really interesting part.

Professor Bones would be teaching Battle Tactics and Strategy, a more general form of the old Hogwarts class called Defense Against the Dark Arts, and Professor Lupin, the new Head of Gryffindor House, would be teaching a new upper level elective called Magical Anthropology. The goal of the class on Magical Anthropology was to promote better relations among Wizards, Muggles, and what Professor McGonnagall referred to as, "Non-Human Sentients." Professor Lupin, she explained, was a werewolf, and therefore uniquely qualified to instruct us on the cultural differences among these groups. I was a little startled to learn that a werewolf would be teaching, but Professor Lupin didn't look nearly as intimidating as Mr. Hagrid, and Professor McGonnagall was so manner-of-fact about it that I realized I wasn't particularly upset. The other students seemed to accept this happily enough too, though Ginny whispered, "Before Fixus Everythingus, that announcement would have caused rioting," and then very seriously added, "I'm not exaggerating."

Then the Headmistress went on to announce that classes in Muggle Science had been added for each year. Given the textbook lists, this announcement had been long-expected by most students, and was met by a quiet murmur of acknowledgement. The murmur became angry when she went on to say that the new courses would be replacing History of Magic. I briefly assumed that History of Magic had been a particularly popular course, but Ginny explained in a low voice, "Most of them count on History of Magic as a chance to catch up on sleep."

Finally McGonnagall introduced the new Professor of Muggle Science, Professor Evans-Verres. McGonnagall explained that some evidence had come to light that Muggle Science had much to offer her own field of Transfiguration, and that she had high hopes that other magical subjects would benefit as well. At Professor Evans-Verres' insistence, Arithmancy would now be a required subject as well, replacing Astronomy, which would now be available as an upper level elective. This arrangement would permit Professor Sinistra the time she would require to bring herself up to speed on the past two hundred years of Muggle Astronomy, as well as to expand her independent research.

"For my own part," the Headmistress continued, "I shall be collaborating directly with Professor Evans-Verres on the development of a new research program on the use of Muggle Science to analyse Transfiguration and the applications of Muggle Science to Transfiguration. I am looking forward to those collaboration as what I am certain shall be a very fruitful endeavour, and I know that all of you will do your best to make Professor Evans-Verres and his wife Petunia Verres-Evans welcome at this school."

At that moment, I heard some slight snickering on the other side of the hall and saw Fred and George whispering to each other at the Gryffindor table.

McGonnagall raised a severe eyebrow, and to my surprise the Weasley twins went instantly silent and looked up, very seriously. The Headmistress spoke then in a low and dangerous voice, "As you may have inferred, my extensive responsibilities will afford me little time for nonsense, and I trust that we shall have none. Have no fear, however, that my duties as Headmistress will be neglected. Should my teaching and research duties every collide with my responsibilities as Headmistress, Deputy Headmaster Flitwick shall be standing by."

Professor Flitwick gave a brief sombre nod of confirmation, and then McGonnagall concluded her speech in lighter tones, welcoming us once more to Hogwarts and wishing us all a restful night.

Author's notes: Chapter 7 should be published on or before April 1, 2014. No, really.

Chapter 10: The Proliferation of Clubs

Things changed after Luna left Chaos Club. Neville apologized to Luna and Ginny, of course, but it was a long time before Ginny calmed down enough to come back, and Fred also stopped showing up as regularly. George still attended meetings, but didn't seem to have as much fun as before. Abbott and a few others also stopped coming.

Things changed outside of Chaos Club, too. It wasn't long afterward that Granger started her own group. I guess that Luna's remarks had gotten her thinking about whether there might be more to understanding the world than the Muggle Science, Hogwarts classes, and the books of the Hogwarts Library, because her club was supposed to focus on Wizarding traditions around the world, as well as Muggle history, anthropology, philosophy, and art. She came over to where Ginny, Luna, and I were eating one day and said that she, Greengrass, Bones, and Draco would be holding a gathering that weekend, and invited Luna to join. She said that Ginny and I could come too.

Ginny and Luna ended up going. I didn't, though I'm not exactly sure why. I guess I've never really felt comfortable around Granger or Greengrass. Maybe it's because of that first day on the Hogwarts Express. I don't know. Granger seems nice enough, but Greengrass always seems cold to me. And Bones always seems too serious, which I guess doesn't help. I guess I'm also a little shy about Granger's celebrity status. I never felt that way about Harry, though. I guess maybe because he always actively reaches out, wants to get other people excited about science and so on.

I think I mostly understood what Granger was thinking, though. When Granger asked that question about why Luna kept saying Draco should know better, I completely understood why. We needed more information, and I'd meant to ask Luna herself the question when I saw her next. The conversation that followed was interesting too, even if it uncovered more tensions within Chaos Club.

Draco said he guessed that she was referring to various traditions kept and stories told in the old families. Most of the stories, he said, dealt with the dire consequences for Wizard children who took magic for granted. These traditions sometimes hinted that magic was a conscious entity that must be appeased, and generally talked about some variant on the concept of respect.

Fred said that he was aware of no such traditions, and Greengrass muttered, "That would be Dumbledore's influence. Crazy old man."

Fred got angry at that, asking what Greengrass was implying about his family, but George again responded more calmly, "Fred, you know perfectly well that our father was as taken in by Dumbledore's charm as anyone," but then he went on, "Actually, in this case I wonder whether Dumbledore might not have been onto something if he was discouraging Wizarding households from propagating old fairytales. All of this sounds like superstition to me."

Draco agreed that a lot of the traditions probably were superstition, adding that his own father was beginning to phase out some of the rituals. Bones and Anthony Goldstein nodded to this, while Greengrass shook her head. Granger said she was sceptical as well, but added, "I don't think we should ignore what Luna says, though. Scepticism means questioning cultural assumptions, but we shouldn't automatically assume that old traditions are wrong, either."

"Be careful, Hermione," said Draco, "Remember that the tales about blood purity are another old tradition..."

Granger had a response ready, "You're making an inappropriate generalization, Draco. Just because some old traditions are incorrect does not imply that they all are, and in this case I don't see that there's any tangible harm being done by assuming that traditions might have been formed for a reason."

"Let's think about this systematically," said Harry, "We can approach it the same way we looked at the blood purity question. It's a good exercise in hypothesis development. What are some ideas of what might really be going on? Let's all take a moment to think about it, then break into groups and generate lists. Later we can compile a list for the room and figure out which ideas are testable."

This idea was familiar territory for us all by now, but as I turned to Anthony to see if he wanted to do some hypothesis brainstorming with me, Granger said darkly, to the room in general, "The thing is, I'm not certain we should be using science to investigate this at all. There's so much we don't know..."

No one had a reply to that, though, and of course it didn't stop us from brainstorming a list of ideas. There are lots of possibilities when you stop to think about it: maybe the traditions were completely made up, maybe they were partially true, or used to be true but had been distorted over the years, maybe the associated folklore itself contained testable hypotheses, and so on. There were all kinds of questions that came up too, such as did magic work differently for families that followed the traditions, and what could we learn from the changes occurring in the Malfoy household?

Granger didn't seem as talkative as usual, though. Maybe that was when she started thinking about starting a group of her own.

Granger wasn't the only one who started a new club around that time. Everybody was talking about the partial breakup of Chaos Club, and when word got out that Granger now had another club of her own, Hogwarts students seemed to suddenly realize that Harry wasn't the only one who could start clubs. Soon there was a chess club (Wizard and Muggle), a debate club, a Magical Artifact Development club, a Muggle athletics club (no wands or broomsticks allowed), and various academic clubs for studying Hogwarts subjects. Tracy Davis, who I'd met once or twice through Chaos Club, posted a bunch of flyers around promoting "A Club for the Study of Darkest Arts and Necromancy: Learn from the Dark Princess of Hogwarts," but I never met anybody who admitted to attending any meetings. On the other hand, Hannah Abbott started a junior healers club, which I hear is pretty popular despite being scheduled in the same time block as Chaos Club.

I hadn't really planned on getting involved with any other clubs or organizations, but then one day after Flying lessons, when I came down I saw that an older student was waiting next to Madam Hooch. He was dark-skinned and had dreadlocks, was muscular and very handsome. I remembered thinking that he was just as beautiful as Draco, but dark instead of pale. I had no idea that he was waiting for me, but as we filed past Madam Hooch he stepped forward.

"You're Colin Creevey?"

I jumped, fumbled with my broomstick, but then nodded. Older students mostly ignore first years, at least outside of clubs.

He grinned, "Sorry to startled you. I'm Lee Jordan, Fred and George Weasley suggested I talk to you."

All I could say was, "Erm?" although I did relax a little bit. Despite their reputation as troublemakers, Fred and George were always friendly with me.

"So, here's the thing," he went on, "Cedric Diggory and I decided that Hogwarts needs a newspaper. We were thinking maybe The Hogwarts Weekly or something like that. The Sorting Hat said you should go into journalism?"

"Oh!" suddenly the conversation made more sense, "Er, yes."

"We don't have a photographer. Fred pointed out that you have a camera, so we were wondering. How would you like to take photographs for the school newspaper?"

Well, couldn't say no to that, now could I? No one (other than Mum, of course, and Dennis when my photographs started moving that one day) had ever acted as though my interest in photography was anything other than a waste of time.

So that's how I became the photographer for the Hogwarts Weekly. One of my Chaos Club photographs of Harry was on the front page of the first issue, for an article Cedric Diggory had written on the proliferation of clubs at Hogwarts. I was pretty proud of that.

Author's notes: Chapter 11 should be out on or before July 1, 2014.

Chapter 11: Homecomings

The Christmas holidays came before I knew it, and as I exited Platform 9 3/4 I was warmly greeted by the whole family. I felt like a hero returning from a great adventure!

Over the holidays, my parents and Dennis asked all sorts of questions: what was Wizard school was like, why we did we need a cauldron, what my favourite classes were, and so on. They were quite impressed when I told them about Flying lessons, and Dennis wanted to know whether I could fly on any old broom. He was disappointed to hear that only magical broomsticks could fly, and was even more disappointed when I explained that we weren't actually allowed to use any magic at all outside of school.

He looked sad about that for a moment, and then frowned, "But what about those moving photographs?"

So I did my best to explain about accidental magic. And then I realized that even though I couldn't do magic, I could still show my family some magical objects. I only had one magical item with me other than my wand, though, and I went to fetch the first issue of the Hogwarts Weekly.

Mum just about bawled when she saw my name, in print, next to the word "photographer." Dennis looked at the cover photo for a bit, and then demanded to know who Harry was and why he was so important. Meanwhile, Dad was very interested read about what kinds of clubs magical students would start.

Questions like these continued throughout the holiday, and I never ran out of things to talk about: the Great Hall with its magical ceiling, the House Elves, the Lake, the Whomping Willow, the talking paintings, and the famous tension between Harry and Granger. I even told them about Science class.

When the holidays ended, I came back to Hogwarts more excited than ever, and the Spring term seemed to fly by. Classes, photography, arguing with Lee and Cedric about the layout for the school newspaper, and of course, Chaos Club.

Over the Spring term, Chaos Club lost a few more students but eventually seemed to stabilize. We continued meeting to work on exercises to help think more rationally, as well as doing a few more experiments, although Granger became an almost perpetual voice of caution whenever magical experiments were proposed. I think Harry would have preferred to move ahead with less argument, but I also slowly realized that he had a ton of respect for Granger, even when they disagreed (which was usually).

Also, Draco seemed to have some sort of crush on Granger, often taking her side even when it seemed he didn't actually understand her arguments. Harry always got annoyed when that happened, and Neville and Padma would roll their eyes and snicker.

There was so much to do, but as the term finally drew to a close, I found I was quite excited to get home again, too. I would have a lot to tell, I knew, and really was looking forward to the sort of welcome I'd gotten at Christmas. I just knew my family would be so excited to hear more about Hogwarts.

I took the long ride to London on the Hogwarts Express, so excited to tell everybody about the Spring term, but it turned out that only Dad was there to pick me up. He'd muttered something about Mum having taken Dennis to the library before driving me home. And while he seemed happy enough to see me, he didn't ask many questions about Hogwarts.

Well, I thought, perhaps Mum and Dennis will be more interested when they get home. Anyhow, I was tired, and headed straight for my bed. But then...

"Colin, you scream like a girl!" Barely home, and there was Dennis, framed in the doorway to our bedroom, laughing like a maniac.

What was I going to say to that? What could I say to that? You'd scream too if you came home and the first thing you saw was a bloody huge snake coiled up on your pillow. That's what I wanted to say, but this was Dennis. Little wanker. He'd be delighted if something like that happened. Of course he would. God, but I miss him, though.

The thing was, though, that since Christmas, while I'd been keeping busy at Hogwarts, things had been happening at home, too. I guess I'd forgotten that life would go on for my family even when I wasn't there.

And now there was a snake on my bed.

I stood with my back pressed against the wall opposite the foot of my bed. I'd barely stepped into the room when I spotted the snake on my pillow and jumped back, almost losing balance as I collided with the wall. I guess I did yell a bit, but I certainly hadn't screamed, no matter what Dennis said. I did have a weird tight feeling in my throat, though.

Dennis must have just got home from the library and had hurried into the room when he heard. Clearly, he thought the whole thing was hilarious.

"Dennis," I finally managed to croak out, "Why?"

The little git just laughed again, then calmly walked over to my bed and picked up the snake. It suddenly didn't look as big as I'd thought at first. Only a little longer than Dennis's forearm, I realized as it coiled around his hand. As he stretched out on his own bed, he spoke softly to the animal and actually stroked it.

I managed to relax a bit, and Dennis glanced up at me, a smug little smile playing at one corner of his mouth, "See, it's safe now," then went on "Nate wouldn't hurt you anyway. She's only a grass snake. But crikey did you yelp."

I edged over to my bed, keeping as far from Dennis's side of the room as I could, then lay down. I wasn't too pleased with putting my head where that slimy beast had been, but it was my bed, darn it.

As I calmed down, Dennis lay with the snake curled on his chest, and told me about how he'd gotten her.

"She's from one of the hedges near Grandma's place in the country. I couldn't just leave her there."

"Dennis, I thought Mum said you shouldn't disturb the creatures that live there. 'They're happiest where they are.' That's what she says every time we're down there." I still wasn't happy about the snake, especially having her on my bed.

Dennis answered right away, though, "Not any more, though, are they?"

That made me sit up. I swung my legs off the edge of my bed and turned to watch Dennis carefully, "What do you mean?"

Dennis looked up in surprise and the dull brown grass snake lifted her head as well. "Blimey," said Dennis, "I guess you haven't heard." He looked at me carefully, then continued, "They're going to bulldoze all those hedgerows at the manor. The new owner wants to put in a big modern farm."

That was a surprise, and not a good one either. I closed my eyes tightly, and images filled my mind. Photographing the fields and hedges from on top of the big rock by the lane. Climbing the big apple tree while Dennis belly-crawled on the ground near the hedges. Walking with Mum and Grandma.

Those hedgerows were hundreds of years old I knew, with all kinds of birds and things nesting in them. Mum and Grandma both loved those fields and hedges like anything. And I'd taken some of my favourite photographs on the manor grounds.

I couldn't believe it. But I was also confused, "I thought the landowner promised never to take those hedges down. Didn't Grandma's group from the town convince him that they were too important to the landscape? I thought he agreed that the manor grounds were worth more left as they are!"

"Well," said Dennis, "I guess he did. But all that is changed now. Something about the new treaty that Prime Minister Major and President Gore put together at that big meeting in Japan. The one about global warming."

"The what now?" I'd heard of global warming. Anthony had told everyone in Chaos Club all about it when he was doing a presentation on solar energy and how magic might improve how solar panels work. Global warming sounded really scary, and I was glad that soon the solar panel designers would have help from the Wizarding community. But Anthony hadn't said anything about any meeting in Japan. We don't talk much about political things in Chaos Club.

"I think the treaty is called the Kyoto Agreement or something. It's supposed to stop global warming."

"What does this have to do with the manor, though?"

Dennis paused, seemed to be trying to remember, then continued slowly, "Well, the climate stuff is mostly about not burning oil and coal and things. But they say some of it is also because they keep cutting down trees, especially rainforests in places like Indonesia and Brazil. The Kyoto Agreement says that countries like England and Europe and America have to burn less coal, but it also says that we have to help other countries protect their rainforests. So they made some kind of system where you can buy and sell permission to burn fuel or cut down trees, so... well... see, the manor owner says that it won't cost him much to cut down the hedges and woods on the grounds, and that he's best off using his land to make money if he also spends some money to protect rainforest in Indonesia."

Dennis looked sad, and I knew just how he felt. The grounds were so beautiful, and I loved thinking about how they'd been like that practically for ever.

But I felt torn, too. Global warming was really scary, and even Dennis had always talked about how important it was not to cut down the jungles in Indonesia because orangutans needed somewhere to live. I felt sad about the hedgerows, but I also realized that I wasn't thinking rationally at all.

I quietly wished I could talk things over with Harry and Anthony, or maybe Draco.

Author's notes: Chapter 12 should be out on or before August 1, 2014.